Chris Reynolds

cpreynolds@outlook.com 07939528710 @cprenno

Personal Statement

An IT / Digital professional with experience in project management, website development and application support. I have excellent communication, presentation and organization skills, and a professional attitude in the workplace. My experience managing development teams, understanding project delivery, and overview of digital services in the public and private sectors will prove invaluable.

Work Experience

Freelance Website Developer & Contract Project Manager - Aug 2018 - Present During my previous role I had decided that I wanted to change my career from Project Management to Web Development. I had a large network of previous colleagues that would be able to assist me in deciding where to focus my education, and as a freelancer I was able to structure my workload so that I was also able to take on personal projects and take online courses to help me make the transition. I did continue with some Project Management work to provide an additional income stream while I was finding my feet. This has given me an opportunity to work on a wide variety of different projects and sites including -

- Building a simple website from scratch for a new Psychiatry clinic that is currently at start-up phase
- Assisting the same business with using Microsoft O365 for secure email and data storage, and guiding them through the online services that they require for the new clinic
- Styling a subscription service for a Marketing Agency
- Project Management and Wordpress build for a Charity website rebrand and rebuild
- Contract Wordpress build for a new website for the Anglican church in Liverpool
- Creating Project Management processes and advice for young businesses that are growing and need to begin to put in a bit of manage their own workflows

I have had help from one of my former colleagues, both with finding work, and receiving training while I have contracted for him, which has got me up to speed with version control in git (Github), css preprocessors (SASS), writing structured CSS with BEM, and php templating and components within the wordpress development environment.

ICT Project Manager - Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

Public Health England

Public Health England ICT department is responsible for a wide variety of infrastructure requirements including the hosting of business critical services and systems, a high performance computing service for rapid response analysts and genome sequencing, and providing the hardware and account management to a varied workforce of ~6000 scientists and civil servants.

Responsibilities

- Managing all sizes of ICT project
- Managing project delivery teams internal and external
- Scheduling work according to departmental priorities & Public Health England strategy
- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Ensuring project documentation is kept up to date and to the department standard
- Regular communication with key stakeholders and project boards
- Setting project scope with other Public Health England departments
- Managing client expectations within an organisation that has a diverse workforce

Head of Digital Production - Apr 2016 to Mar 2017

Tokyo

Liverpool

Tokyo is a leading Full Service Digital Agency based in London and Liverpool. They create digital products for all sizes and shapes of clients across the technology spectrum, specialising in beautifully designed high traffic high profile websites, CMS platform delivery for multinational pharmaceutical firms, and product development using bleeding edge technology.

Responsibilities

- Managing the project delivery team in the Liverpool Studio
- Scheduling work and managing project change
- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Oversight of client management and communications
- Managing project budgets and standardizing documentation processes across retained and project based clients
- Requirements gathering, proposal writing and attending pitches
- Managing teams of remote workers and contractors

Project Manager - October 2014 to Mar 2016

Digital Services
Liverpool City Council

The Digital Services team provides solutions to improve service delivery for Liverpool City Council's public access channels and support digital applications used in the public and private sector.

Responsibilities:

- Managing the transition from Liverpool Direct Limited back to Liverpool City Council
- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Kick off meetings with clients and creating project scope/SORs
- Managing project budgets and documenting projects (SOR/PID/RAG/Plans)
- Ensuring that organizational channel shift will lead to increase in digital service delivery
- Managing teams of developers and designers
- Managing change in the ICT environment
- Deploying third party systems
- Standardizing internal project processes and creating a sustainable project framework
- Scheduling of development time and ensuring delays or change requests in projects have minimal impact to the development schedule

Digital Project Manager - Feb 2014 to May 2014

Rippleffect

Liverpool

Rippleffect is an award winning Digital Agency owned by Trinity Mirror PLC. The projects team deliver a variety of showcase sites, content managed solutions and applications. These are produced for a variety of clients including retailers, football clubs, public bodies and large companies.

Responsibilities:

- Prince2 Practitioner
- Manage a portfolio of high profile clients
- Lead internal and external teams through the project delivery cycle, from scoping to handover.
- Scoping, planning and specifying projects, managing them effectively within timings and to budget.
- Build relationships with clients and be the main point of project contact, managing expectations and driving internal resource, clients and third party suppliers to ensure deliverables are on time.
- Create and maintain effective project documentation
- Fundamental understanding of Project Management processes and methodologies.
- Excellent verbal and written communication and ability to lead multiple projects simultaneously.
- Understand technologies applicable to projects and facilitation of the resolution of technical issues.

Project Manager - November 2012 to Feb 2014

Digital Services Liverpool Direct Limited Responsibilities:

- Agile and Prince2 Practitioner
- Waterfall and Agile project management as appropriate
- Kick off meetings with clients and creating project scope/SORs
- Managing project budgets and documenting projects (SOR/PID/RAG/Plans)
- Ensuring that organizational channel shift will lead to increase in digital service delivery
- Managing teams of developers and designers
- Managing change in the ICT environment
- Deploying third party systems
- Scheduling of development time and ensuring delays or change requests in projects have minimal impact to the development schedule

Geodata Technician and Project Support - February 2009 to November 2012 Geodata and Digital Services Liverpool Direct Limited

The Geodata team are responsible for managing Liverpool City Council's access to spatial data, supporting MapInfo GIS, analyzing, cleaning and matching large data sets and providing an online geospatial service to Liverpool City Council.

Responsibilities:

- Management and maintenance of the Local Land and Property Gazetteer
- Liaison between a wide range of services within LCC
- Improving data quality and synergy between service areas
- Processing of data within GIS programmes
- Advanced MapInfo user
- Management of ISO9001 core processes and quality assurance processes
- Supporting Digital project managers with internal and external projects

GIS Technician - October 2007 to December 2007

Projects and Planning Team Lancashire County Council Environment Directorate

I gained work experience within this team as a GIS technician. My duties included using ArcView to present spatial data, create maps and base plans. These were used by planners, designers and architects to visualize projects to be carried out locally. The environment directorate works toward improving communities and create higher quality of life for residents. Social deprivation is a big factor in choosing locations for these projects.

Education

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt -

The Knowledge Academy, Manchester

Umbraco Level 1 Practitioner - May 2015

Percipient Studios, Manchester

DSDM Agile Practitioner – Dec 2014

Datrix Training, Liverpool

PRINCE2 Practitioner – June 2012 (Valid until May 2017)

Datrix Training, Liverpool

BSc, Physical Geography with Management (2:1) – September 2005 - June 2008

Edge Hill University, Ormskirk

Personal Interests

Cyclist – I started cycling to save money and keep fit on my commute but found that it is a great hobby and enjoy road biking in the UK and abroad, and now race and train with Liverpool Century Road Club.

Dog Walker – I enjoy the routine and time out of the house whatever the weather with my ex-racing greyhounds.

References

Zahid Hussain - Head of Program Delivery Public Health England zahid.hussain@phe.gov.uk

Adam Hughes - Director

Forward Theory - adam@forwardtheory.co.uk

Dan James - Creative Director Tokyo Digital - dan@tokyo.uk

Will Costello – Head of Digital Services
Digital Services, 5th Floor, Cunard Building, Water Street Liverpool, L3 1AH
william.costello@liverpool.gov.uk